Ahmed Ramadan

Senior UI Designer

Riyadh Saudi Arabia+966540441989

Bē behance.net/aali

in linkedin.com/in/aali2

Summary

With solid portfolio of Senior UI Designer at Alinma Bank, based in Saudi Arabia, and with more than six years of experience, I believe that my professional experience and educational and training background make me one of the most qualified candidates for this position.

My career history started in 2010. I started as a freelancer, after that I joined a Cairo-based company for web solutions as a Junior web designer working on the clients' projects. Today, I am proficient in various types of designing work; including: Mobile Apps, Website Templates and a lot of Graphic Design tracks.

I had the opportunity to be involved in different types of projects; in the field of education, media, real estate, e-commerce, corporate profiles and individuals' portfolios. Also, I worked with different types of companies; both corporates and startups. You can check a summary of my portfolio through this link: http://www.be.net/aali

I am capable of working in a team and managing the delivery of projects in the best way. Furthermore, I excel at:

UI Design (colors, typography, white space), Graphic Design (Photoshop & Illustrator) Prototyping (Invisionapp, Marvel App and Uxpin), Wireframing (Balsamiq - Illustrator - Office tools),

Web Design (Responsive web design, Front end development, Wordpress),

Mobile Apps Design (Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch & Figma).

Lately, I have been searching for a new challenge in a new field for me. I am prepared to become an active team member who can add positive contributions to your organization.

Work Experience

Senior UI Designer

Mar 2016 - Present

Alinma Bank

- Working as UI Designer under IT-SERVICE CREATION department inside the bank.
- Create Sketches, Wireframes and designs for Alinma Investment websites, like Alinma Investment & Alinma Tadawul.
- Fixing the UI design/ UI devenment issues in the current websites.
- Fixing the UX issues as a part of our work based on user interviews and analytics reports.
- Working on Tadawul System which helping traders in Daily life in Saudi Arabia.

UX Designer

Apr 2015 - Feb 2016

Youtta Free Internet

- Responsible for every thing related to the app in design side e.g. creating the Wireframes, Prototypes and Mockups.
- Responsible for creating the visual design of the app like app screen layout designs using Graphic design programs e.g Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator.
- Collaborating on user experience planning and User experience process with the product owner.
- Create the user flows and the app scenarios.
- Responsible for creating Youtta's website layout.

UI Developer Jun 2015 - Nov 2015

311 Solutions

- Responsible for creating and preparing markup files for cross platform apps like Phonegap.
- Responsible for Fixing Markup issues in current projects.
- Create responsive layouts for websites and mobile.
- Responsible for UI Development process from receiving design files like PSD to Backend and Quality Control.

Senior UI Designer

Aug 2014 - Dec 2014

Nilecode

- Create and prepare wireframes, sketches and prototypes for websites and mobile applications.
- Study and discussion of different ideas and concepts to take out a new idea to meet the user needs.
- Create websites layout using graphic programs like Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Follow Android & iOS guidelines to create a visual design for mobile apps.
- Create Mobile apps screens layout and slice it to deliver to the developer.
- Collaborate with different teams to finish websites and apps as same design and user need.
- Learn more about User experience and Usability.

Web & Graphic Designer

Feb 2012 - Apr 2014

Cimaat

- Meeting with Clients and know website details and what they need exactly.
- Creating Wireframes for web sites.
- Design website interface on Photoshop and other graphic programs.
- Slicing PSD to markup language HTML & CSS & jQuery.
- Convert web pages from markup language to WordPress theme.
- Building WordPress Themes and HTML templates from scratch.
- Testing web pages cross browsers and make sure that is compatible and does not contain problems.

Junior Web Designer

Jan 2011 - Nov 2011

Top Line

- Check the clients tickets on the support panel.
- Design website interfaces using Photoshop, Ilustrator ..etc.
- Slicing PSD to Frond end code like HTML & CSS & jQuery.
- Convert web pages from markup language to PHP web templates.
- Testing web pages cross browsers and make sure that is compatible and does not contain problems.

Founder Sep 2010 - Feb 2016

Hawy

Web solutions and Mobile apps services

Skills

User Interface Design Mobile apps design Web Design Wireframes **Prototypes** User flows A/B Testing Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Sketch



Portfolio

Behance: http://www.behance.net/aali **Google Drive:** https://goo.gl/4FJ8WC

Education

Faculty of Law 2006 - 2010

Tanta University